准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
大块头
海绵宝宝
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
该让自己变大变壮了
It's time to grow myself large and wide
你好  海绵宝宝
Howdy, SpongeBob
近来如何
How's it going?
别靠太近  珊迪
Not too close, Sandy
我一举重就会发臭
I tend to get smelly when I'm pumping iron
来看看
Check it out
你真的好臭
Well, you're smelly
全都要归功于
All thanks to
先进举重设备
my state-of-the-art weight set
微笑
我无意让你失望  海绵宝宝
I don't want to disappoint you, SpongeBob
可拿这些来举重不会有进步的
but you won't see any progress lifting those
真的吗
Really?
对  如果想要这样的胳膊的话
That is, if you want arms like these
或者这样的
Or these
那看来我需要有人来帮忙了
Well, maybe I could use a little help
如果你想要我这样的胳膊
Well, if you want arms like mine
就要参加我的训练课程
you just got to follow my training program
真的吗
Really?
那可太棒了  珊迪
That'd be great, Sandy
我都能看到我未来的样子了
I can see me now
晚安  小蜗
Good night, Gary
好耶  那样的话就啥都不一样了
Yeah, that would change everything
早上五点来我家
Be at my place at 5:00 am
戴个水头盔来
And you'll need a water helmet
加油  海绵宝宝
Come on, SpongeBob
才俯卧撑而已
It's only pushups
加油  加油
Come on, come on
你能行的
You can do it
一
One
好了  手举起来
All right, put them up
在起来了
They're up
感受到热量燃烧吗
Feeling the burn?
我有感觉了
I'm feeling something
既然你已经热完身了
Well, now that we've got you warmed up
该来压压手了
it's time for the arm cruncher
压手  不错
Arm cruncher, great
这只松鼠想杀了我
This squirrel's trying to kill me
到了
This is it
太好了  珊迪
That's great, Sandy
我玩得好开心
I sure had fun
改天再来健身吧
We'll have to do it again sometime--
拜
Bye
这健身根本没什么用
This working out thing isn't working out
你
You
废物
Wimpy
我是只花生虫
"I'm a little peanut worm"
你是不是废到健不了身
Are you too much of a wimp to work out?
你是不是像海绵一样弱
Are you a weakling built like a sponge?
现在
Well, now
你也能够拥有肌肉
You, too, can have muscles
快用船锚胳膊
With anchor arms
可以直接套胳膊上
They slip on like a glove
充气即可使用
Just add air
你想要多大呢
How big do you want them?
正常大小
Normal?
青筋暴起
Veiny?
想要泡妞
And for the ladies
长毛
hairy
买船锚胳膊以前我还是个废物
I was a wimp before anchor arms
现在我是健美好手  人人都爱我
Now I'm a jerk, and everybody loves me
立刻下单吧  废物
So order now, wimp
真是个好办法
Now, that's a good idea
我想跟他一个样
I want to be just like him
对  我一定要去打电话
Yeah, I've got to get to a phone
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
你好啊  蟹老板
Ahoy, Mr. Krabs
珍珍的妈啊
Mother-of-pearl
关
贻贝海滩
[ mussel（贻贝）与muscle（肌肉）谐音 ]
大家好
Hi, guys
海绵宝宝  是你吗
SpongeBob, is that you?
你们以为是谁
Who are you expecting?
小蒂姆
Tiny Tim?
[ Tiny Tim：S01E01插曲"Livin' in the Sunlight,
Lovin' in the Moonlight"演唱者 ]
先等一下
Wait, wait
还真是大啊
Big, aren't they?
老兄  你身材真好
Dude, you're ripped
谢谢
你
我一直都在健身
I've been working out
先等一下
Excuse me a second
好
Yeah
谁想去果汁摊吗
Anyone for the juice bar?
果汁摊
我跟你说  他好大
I'm telling you, he's huge
你们有在哪看到过海绵宝宝吗
Have you guys seen SpongeBob anywhere?
你是说大块头海绵宝宝吗
You mean MuscleBob BuffPants?
他在里面
He's in there
随便
Whatever
谢谢
Thanks
我每天早上都吃二十个生鸡蛋
I start off with 20 raw eggs every day
我就是这样
but that's just me
不好意思
Pardon me
健身就是我的一生
Working out is my life
我还记得我从前
I remember when I used to
还是那边那人的身材的时候
look like that guy over there
谁  我吗
Who, me?
我也还记得我从前
I remember when I used to
还是你那样的身材的时候
look like you, too
可那已经过了好长时间了
But that was a long time ago
饮料好了  先生
Here's your drink, sir
谢谢
Thank you
对
Yeah
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
什么
What
你从哪弄到这身肌肉的
Where'd you get those muscles?
我自己制定了一套健身计划
I've created my own workout routine
然后让我有了惊人的成效
that's giving me amazing results--
我感觉就从来没这么好过
Yeah, I have never felt better
好家伙  你有什么诀窍
Heck, what's your secret?
什么
What?
你的健身秘诀
Your secret workout--
是什么
What is it?
他好高明
Yeah, he's smart
对
Yeah
那个  我
Well, I, uh
首先我举起手  这样子
First I take my hand and I do this
你开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
这些肌肉说谎了吗
Do these muscles lie?
真高兴能看到
I'm glad to see
你找到了适合你的健身计划
you've found an exercise program that works for you
对  你的健身计划
Yeah, your workout routine
对我而言力度远远不够
wasn't quite tough enough for me
对这结果我无法反驳
Can't argue with those results
你现在要做的
What you need to do now
就是要测试一下你这身肌肉
is put those muscles to the test
什么意思
What do you mean?
贻贝海滩船锚投掷大赛
The big mussel beach anchor toss competition
今天举行
It's today
所有人都会到场
Everybody will be there
你饮料好了
Here's your drink
既然你有这胳膊  你表现绝对不俗
With those arms, you'll do great
我不太确定
Well, I'm not sure
来吧  去参加吧
Come on, let's go
就现在
Right now?
等一下   珊迪
Wait, wait, Sandy
我觉得这不太
I don't think it's such a
珊迪  等等
Sandy, wait
到了
Here it is--
报名表
The sign-in list
船锚投掷大赛
此处报名
投入口
不好
Oh, no
船锚投掷大赛
参赛者姓名
好了
Okay
珊迪
Sandy
奇克斯
Cheeks
等等珊迪  先别签
Wait, Sandy, don't sign just yet
投入口
好了
Okay
等等
Wait
海绵
SpongeBob
宝宝
SquarePants
珊迪
Sandy
等等
Wait
没事的  海绵宝宝
It's okay, SpongeBob
我已经帮你报完名了
I already signed your name in
太棒了
Oh, great
谢了  珊迪
Thanks, Sandy
话筒开了吗
Are we on?
欢迎来到
Welcome to
酷乐湖第八届年度船锚投掷大赛
the Goo Lagoon Eighth Annual Anchor Toss Competition
准备好了吗  海绵宝宝
Ready, SpongeBob?
对  好了
Oh, yeah, sure
没问题
No problem
能在上面加点芥末吗
Can I get some mustard on that?
首先上场的是  鲸鱼唐姆
First up, Dom the Whale
200码
200 yards
来看看即时回放
Let's see an instant replay
太神了
Amazing
接下来上场的是  龙虾拉里
Up next, Larry the Lobster
210码
210 yards
珊迪奇克斯上场了
Here goes Sandy Cheeks
510码
510 yards
超神
Fabulous
超越我的成绩吧  海绵宝宝
Beat that, SpongeBob
接下来是  海绵宝宝
Up next, SpongeBob SquarePants
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
开个玩笑
Just kidding
那个海绵宝宝也太好笑了
That SpongeBob's funnier than ears on an acorn
要完蛋了
This is it
他们都要发现我这都是假的了
They're all going to find out I'm a fake
不能放弃
I can't give up
必须拼一把
I've got to try
我能行的
I can do it
我有船锚胳膊
I've got anchor arms
我不是废物
I'm no wimp
我是健美好手
I'm a jerk
正常
强壮
超级
健美好手
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
他应该是输了
I think he lost
珊迪
Sandy
再做一百下
I want a hundred more
好疼
It hurts
一
One
二
two
三
three
四
four
终于帮你找到适合你的运动了
I think we finally found an exercise for you
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
八
Eight
九
nine
十
ten
能帮我拿一下吗
Can you get that?
章鱼哥
不友好的鬼魂
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
我有没有跟你说过你有多美吗
Have I told you how beautiful you are?
你的爪子
Your tentacles
你的鼻子
your nose
你的眼睛
your eyes
不太匀称
A little lopsided
好了
There
既然我已经在蜡像中永垂不朽了
And now that I've been immortalized in wax
这就表示我击败了整个艺术传媒
I have conquered all artistic media
快啊  我宝贵样貌的映照
Come on, my precious reflection
笑一个
Smile
快前进  派大星
Hike, Patrick, hike
你已经输三分了
You just lost three points
一
One
二
Two
五
Five
G7
G-7
G-7?
将军  将军
King me, king me
我输了
I lose
不过今天不是星期二  派大星
But it's not Tuesday, Patrick
真该死
Tartar sauce
你们两个无脊椎动物在搞什么鬼
What are you invertebrates doing?
不知道
We don't know
派大星  你知道现在几点了吗
Hey, Patrick, do you know what time it is?
知道  章鱼哥
Yeah, Squidward
现在
It's
是该找别的游戏玩的点
Time to find some other game to play
现在要玩什么
Now what?
我们可以来回抛接这块贝壳
We could toss that shell back and forth
好
Okay
准备
Ready
去接
Go
我去捡
I got it
记住  派大星
Remember, Patrick
谁捡到就归谁
Finders keepers
在那
There it is
我来捡
I got it
奖励分
Bonus points
派大星
Patrick?
章鱼哥好像出事了
I think something's wrong with Squidward
他好像失去意识了
He looks unconscious
不用担心
Don't worry
我知道要怎么办
I know how to do this
快下去  派大星
Get off him, Patrick
你在担心个什么劲啊
What are you worried about?
他看着已经好多了
He looks better already
可他摸着还是冷的
But he still feels cold
那就去把他放到暖点的地方去
Well, let's go put him in the warm
你觉得他会没事吗
Do you think he'll be okay?
你可担心得太过头了
You know, you worry too much
海绵宝宝  有派大星在这
The Patrick is here and, SpongeBob
我非常了解头部创伤  相信
I know a lot about head injuries, believe
我
Me
你鞋子上的是什么
What's that on your shoe?
不知道
I don't know
看着有点像
It kind of looks like
章鱼哥
Squidward
把他弄下去
Get him off me
走开
Go away
不对  这块要放这
No, no, that part goes here
哦对
Oh, yeah
对  就这样
Yeah, th-that's it
就快好了
We're almost there
有用了
It's working
我们能行的
We can do this
对  有用了
Yeah, this is working
有用了
This is working
起效了
It's working
派大星  根本没用
Patrick, this isn't working
你看
Look
我不知道怎么说才好
I don't know how to say it
我们的朋友章鱼哥
but our old pal Squidward
他
he's
他去世了
he's pushing up daisies
我还以为他死了
I thought he was dead
你们来这干什么
What are you doing here?
不
No
你们两个是想说什么
Well, are you two going to say something
还是要我
or do I have to
不  别过来
No, stay back
你们两个有什么毛病
What is the matter with you two?
别
Don't
别伤害我们
Don't hurt us
都是意外
It was an accident
你们两个到底在说什么
What are you two talking about?
看看你们两个对我干的好事
Look what you've done to me
要是让我逮到你们  我就
When I get my hands on you, I'll
求你了  章鱼哥鬼魂先生
Please, Mr. Squidward ghost
求你不要生气了
Spare us your ghostly anger
对  章鱼哥鬼魂先生
Yes, Mr. Squidward's ghost
求你不要缠我们的身
Please don't haunt us
你要什么我们就做什么
We'll do anything you want
求你饶过我们吧
Just have mercy on us
够了
Enough
都听好
Listen up
章鱼哥鬼魂今天异常大方
Squidward's ghost is feeling
unusually generous today
他已经决定不让你们受苦
He hath decided to spare ye a horrible fate
你们就只要顺从我的所有兴致
All ye must do is tend to my every whim
满足我的要求
and tickle my fancy on demand
是不是还要算上
Does that include
安静
Quiet
快去照我吩咐的做
Now, do as you're told
免得惹章鱼哥生气
lest ye incur the wrath of Squidward
他们好像特地弄了个美白霜
I think they make a cream for that now
这儿行吗
Here?
太热了
Too hot
这儿呢
Here?
不行  太湿了
No, too wet
继续走
Keep going
这儿呢
Here?
太散漫了  罗特列克
Too loose, Lautrec
[ 图卢兹·罗特列克（Toulouse-Lautrec）：法国画家
too loose（太散漫）与Toulouse（图卢兹）谐音 ]
鱼剧团
太累了
Too tired
完美
Perfect
我感觉
I feel
好想要东西
needy
奴隶们  给我拿点食物
Slaves, fetcheth me some nourishment
保证给最新鲜的  鬼魂
Only the freshest, o spooky one
从藤上现摘的葡萄  鬼魂大人
A grape fresh from the vine, your ghostliness
照你的意愿剥的香蕉  鬼魂大人
A banana peeled to your liking your incorporialness
一个西瓜
One watermelon
从施过粪肥的地里现摘的  鬼魂大人
Fresh from the manure field your spookiness
你不满意吗
Art thou not pleased?
差不多得了
Enough of that
我现在想吃点别的
I want something else to eat now
要非常难找的东西
Something that's very difficult to find
你想要吃什么  主人
What do you hunger for, master?
你想要什么  我们就会去找
Whatever you want, we'll find it
我们会去找
We'll find it
樱桃派
Cherry pie
你从哪弄来的
Where'd you get that?
我找到的
I found it
那就再去找
Well, go find it again
海绵宝宝  过来
SpongeBob, get over here
转身
Now spin around
好多了
That's better
原地跑步
Now jog in place
说  侧腹牛排
Say "flank steak"
侧腹牛排
Flank steak
我好像快要喜欢上这生活了
I think I'm beginning to like this
停
Stop
拿这个用心给我吹首曲子
Now play me an elaborate song with this
可这就只是张卫生纸
But this is just a piece of tissue paper
天啊
Oh, my
非得要自作主张是吧
Always have to have it our way, don't we?
我做不到
I can't do it
希望你们今晚没什么安排
Well, I hope you don't have any plans tonight
因为等我听到曲子之前你休想走
because you're not allowed to leave that spot
till I hear a song
怎么回事
What's this?
干活期间打瞌睡
Napping on the job?
你应该要给我奏乐的
You're supposed to be making music for me
作为这份无礼态度的惩罚
As punishment for this insolence
章鱼哥鬼魂命令你们
Squidward's ghost commandeth you
去清理他的后室
to clean out his back room
我找到了
I found it
我要了
I'll take that
是  鬼魂大人
Yes, your ghostliness
好好玩
This is fun
派大星  准备好了吗
Patrick, are you ready for this?
好了
Yes
好  走吧
Okay, let's go
派大星  你来不来
Patrick, are you coming?
来
Yes
派大星  要往这走
Patrick, it's this way
哪
Where?
这
Here
来了
Coming
要怎么把这团乱清理干净
How are we going to clean up all this mess?
很简单
It's easy
把墙纸撕掉就好
Just tear this wallpaper off
你看  你少撕了点
Oh, look, you missed some
来看看
Let's see
是本漫画  看这个
It's a comic book, and look at this--
是飞天魔鬼的起源
It's the origin of the Flying Dutchman
上面说他死后
It says when he died
飞天魔鬼的
悲惨命运
就是这样
儿童世界
促销
人们用他的遗体当橱窗展示架
they used his body as a window display
现在他不断出没于七大洋
Now he haunts the seven seas
自此过后
他永远出没于
七大洋中
就因为他永世不得安宁
because he was never put to rest
你不明白吗  派大星
Well, don't you get it, Patrick?
我们要去购物了
We're going to go shopping?
不对
No
我们要让可怜的章鱼哥安息
We're going to put poor old Squidward to rest
搞什么鬼
What the heck was that?
一切的开始
Initiation
那是你仪式的第一部分
That was part one of your ceremony
什么的仪式
Ceremony for what?
我们要让你安息
We're going to put you to rest
我才不想要安息
I don't want to be put to rest
我只想要你们干完杂活
All I want are those chores done
你们把后室清理干净了没
Now, did you clean the back room yet?
清好了
Yeah
真的吗
Really?
我进去检查
I'm going to go check
好  进去吧
Okay, get in
你们疯了吗
Are you crazy?
我才不进去那玩意
I'm not getting in that thing
可你说我们可以让你安息啊
But you said we could put you to rest
我可没说过那种话
I didn't say anything like that
现在快滚出我家
Now, get out of my house
好
Okay
现在怎么了
Now what?
我写了  这里埋葬着章鱼哥
I wrote "Here lies Squidward
你们可能不记得他  但是
You may not remember him, but"
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
这样够深了吗
Does this look deep enough?
海绵宝宝  别闹了
SpongeBob, cut that out
看  送葬队到了
Look, the mourners have arrived
章鱼哥
Oh, Squidward
我们得知你死之后  马上就来了
We all came as soon as we were sure you were dead
海绵宝宝  你是想送我进疯人院吗
SpongeBob, are you trying to put me in the nuthouse?
不对  只送进这个坑
No, just into this hole
海绵宝宝  我要向你坦白个事
SpongeBob, I have a confession to make
你是个秃头
You're bald?
我才不是秃头
No, I'm not bald
我还活着
I'm alive
现在快把墓碑拆了
Now, get rid of that tombstone
叫你朋友赶紧回去
and tell all your friends to go home
可是
But
快叫
Do it
回去吧
Go home
可是我
But I
主人
Master
我不是你主人
I'm not your master
我是你邻居
I'm your neighbor
帮个忙  别来帮个忙了
Now, do me a favor and stop doing me favors
如你所愿  主人
As you wish, master
天啊  他真的骗得我们团团转
Boy, he really had us fooled
不对派大星  他才是被骗的
No, Patrick, he's the fool
他不承认自己是鬼魂
He's a ghost in denial
他现在最需要我们
He needs us now more than ever
你说得对
You're right
他真的很需要上西天
He really needs to get up to the great beyond
派大星  你再说一遍
Patrick, say that again
一遍
That again
不对  是另外那句
No, the other thing
不对  是你之前说的
No, what you said before when
算了
Never mind
我有办法了
I've got an idea
算了  我有办法了
Never mind, I've got an idea
我够不到他
I can't reach him
再用力吹
Blow harder
他飞升了
There he goes
是不是很美
Isn't he beautiful?
他到底要升到多高啊
How high's he going to go?
派大星  他会一路升到西天去
All the way, Patrick, up to the great beyond
再见  朋友
Good-bye, friend
旅途愉快
Happy trails
不客气
You're welcome
他现在到世界的另一边去了
He's on the other side now
对
Yeah
他到更好的地方去了
He's in a better place